Guide to the Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims and Henry Ward Beecher collection ARC.212
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Henry Ward Beecher, 1819-1958; 16.5 Cubic Feet
  - Section 3: Sermons, Lectures, and Publications
    - Sermon: James 46:5 (June 28) (handwritten)., 1885 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sermon: John 11:44 (July 5) (handwritten)., 1885 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Eulogy on General Grant" (October 22) (handwritten)., 1885 (Box 5, Item 5)
    - Sermons (TJE, printed, 1892)., 1885-1886 (Box 5, Item 6)
    - "Significance of the Term Hatred as Used by Christ" (January 10) (handwritten)., 1886 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Sermon Notes for Philistines 1: 15-18 (February 21) (handwritten)., 1886 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sermons (typescripts and printed)., 1886 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sermons (TJE, printed, 1892)., 1886-1887 (Box 5, Item 7)
    - Sermons (printed)., circa 1887 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "Getting up in the Morning,"Luke 16:4, and Romans 14: 12 (handwritten)., undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Sermon: Romans: 2:4-5 (typescript)., undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "Two Hundred and Forty Years Ago" (handwritten)., undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "Young America" (handwritten)., undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sermons (typescripts)., undated (Box 6, Folder 6-9)
    - Sermons and sermon notes (handwritten)., undated (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - Sermon notes (handwritten)., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "The Lord's Prayer No. III" (typescript)., undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Reports of Beecher's sermons (handwritten, typescripts, and printed)., 1856-1887 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Prayers and Announcements (typescripts)., 1860-1869 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Prayers (typescripts)., 1872-1879 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Lecture/ Sermon Notebook (handwritten)., 1848-1849 (Box 6, Item 1)
    - Bible Lecture Prayers (TJE, printed, 1892)., 1878-1879 (Box 6, Item 2)
    - Announcements (typescripts)., 1872-1879 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Prayers and Announcements (typescripts)., 1840s-1880s (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Prayers published in Plymouth Chimes (typescripts)., 1861-1887 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Promotional material for Norwood., undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Metaphors and Similes: reviews and correspondence., 1896 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - A Treasury of Illustration: reviews and correspondence., 1904 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Remarks on Preaching (TJE, printed, circa 1890)., undated (Box 7, Item 1)
    - Bound stenographic typescript of Miscellaneous Sayings (TJE, printed, circa 1890)., undated (Box 7, Item 2)
    - Last Morning Prayers (TJE, printed, 1892)., 1886-1887 (Box 7, Item 3)
    - Compiled reviews of A Book of Prayer (bound)., 1892 (Box 7, Item 4)
    - Compiled reviews of Bible Studies (bound)., 1893 (Box 8, Item 1)
    - Bound "draft" typescript of Pictures and Music, initialed by T.J. Ellinwood., undated (Box 8, Item 2)
    - Bound stenographic typescript of Birds and Flowers (TJE)., undated (Box 8, Item 3)
    - Bound stenographic typescript of Advice to Young People (TJE)., undated (Box 8, Item 4)
    - Bound stenographic typescript of Concerning Children (TJE)., undated (Box 8, Item 5)
    - Bound stenographic typescript of Biographical Sketches (TJE)., undated (Box 8, Item 6)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence., circa 1877, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook of clippings re: sermons, lectures and some correspondence., 1860-1864 (Box 40, Item 1)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      This scrapbook is too fragile to be handled by researchers and is restricted from use.
    - Sermons printed in Christian Union and Christian World, 1872-1886 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Section 4: Beecher in Indianapolis
    - 1840 Letter to Lewis J. Cist from Henry Ward Beecher; letter re: call to Indianapolis; 2 clips; memoir of Beecher there; hundredth anniversary program, 1840, 1913, 1927, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Section 5: Beecher and Plymouth Church
    - Newspaper accounts of Beecher's activities at the church., circa 1860-1885 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Page from anti-evolution work "Evolution Decadent"., undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Silver Wedding ephemera: tickets., 1872 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Silver Wedding programs and anthems., 1872 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Ribbon from Silver Wedding., 1872 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Account of Silver Wedding by Horatio C. King (3 copies)., 1873 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Beecher's 70th birthday celebration: ticket, newsclippings and programs., 1883 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Section 6: Beecher's Involvement in the Anti- Slavery Movement
    - Church's position on slavery., circa 1850, 1942, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Auctioning of slaves at Plymouth: written reminiscences (including typescripts and other reproductions of documents circa 1839-circa 1860)., 1927 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Original tax return of Charlotte Collins of Charleston, including slaves as property., 1819 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Statement on slavery from British churches to Congregational Churches of New York., 1853 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Rose Ward Hunt: newspaper clippings re: return to church for celebration of 80th anniversary of Beecher's first sermon preached at Plymouth Church., 1927 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
    - Audio cylinder of Rose Ward Hunt remarks, 1927 (Box 74, Item 1)
      The audio cylinder is not available for research. Researchers should use the digital recording available on the Internet Archive.
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Audio cylinder recording has been digitized, and the recording can be accessed on the Internet Archive.
    - Scrapbook: clippings and correspondence to Beecher., 1858-1868 (Box 41, Item 1)
  - Section 7: Political Climate
    - Typescript about "Beecher's Volunteers," letter relating Lincoln's attendance of a Plymouth service, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Gen. U.S. Grant memorial ribbon., circa 1885 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Andrew Johnson: leaf from account book., 1834-1837 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Letter from Admiral John A. Dahlgren (recipient unknown) and engraved image., 1861 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Transcript of farewell address to Beecher from Britain sent to Plymouth, and Plymouth's response., 1863 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Death of Lincoln: photo of portrait, memorial ribbon, manuscript of the "Action of the [Washington, DC] City Government on the occasion of the Assassination of President Lincoln," 3 pieces Confederate currency., 1863,1865 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Letter to Tilton from Cheever and engraved image of Cheever., 1864 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Fort Sumter flag raising program., 1865 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Letter from Sen. Charles Sumner to Chandler re: reconstruction and engraving of Sumner., 1867 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Newsclipping and "comic book style" history re: Beecher and Lincoln., circa 1937 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Section 8: Beecher- Tilton Trial
    - Pamphlets of trial proceedings., 1875-1876 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Newsclippings re: trial., 1874-1934 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Invitation to party celebrating 10th anniversary of the Tiltons., 1865 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Article on Beecher- Tilton Case., 1920 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Theodore Tilton vs. Henry Ward Beecher (Verbatim Report): vol. 2., 1875 (Box 10, Item 1)
    - Theodore Tilton vs. Henry Ward Beecher (Verbatim Report): vol. 2, vol. 3 (2 copies); Official Report vol. 2., 1875 (Box 11, Item 1-4)
    - Copies of the New York Tribune containing articles on Beecher-Tilton case (July 29-Aug 28), 1874 (Box 42, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook of newsclippings re: trial., 1873-1876 (Box 43, Item 1)
    - Mounted political cartoons., circa 1874 (Box 73, Item 1)
    - Six Issues of The Daily Graphic, August, 1874 - October, 1874 (Box 77)
  - Section 9: Death
    - Ephemera: flowers and leaves from casket, copies of "His [Beecher's] Last Prayer," tickets to funeral, order of service, ribbon/ Easter card from Beecher(?)., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts and printed poems., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Printed, single items., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Brooklyn Baptist Social Union: Beecher Memoriam (March 17)., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Sermon of Rev. Armitage, at Plymouth (March 27)., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Newsclippings of death and funeral., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Eulogy by Joseph Parker., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Henry Ward Beecher: A Sermon" by John Chadwick (May)., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Plymouth Sunday School Memorial (February)., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - General eulogies of Beecher., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Beecher Memorial Album (4 copies)., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
    - "I am Resolved What to Do": Beecher's last sermon., 1887 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Hand calligraphed memorial album by Henry E. Nelmes; 2 photos of an elderly woman (Eunice Beecher?)., 1887 (Box 44, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: Brooklyn Citizen., 1887 (Box 45, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: Brooklyn Daily Eagle., 1887 (Box 46, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: Brooklyn Union., 1887 (Box 47, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: New York Herald., 1887 (Box 48, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: various papers., 1887 (Box 49, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: New York Sun., 1887 (Box 50, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: New York Times., 1887 (Box 51, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: New York Tribune., 1887 (Box 52, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: New York World., 1887 (Box 53, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: Miscellaneous., 1887-1891 (Box 54, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: Miscellaneous., 1887 (Box 55, Item 1)
    - News clipping scrapbook: Miscellaneous., 1887-1891 (Box 56, Item 1)
    - Henry Ward Beecher Funeral Tickets, Sermon Extracts, and Autograph Cards of Lyman Beecher and Harriet Beecher Stowe, 1887 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Section 10: Memorials
    - Beecher Memorial Ephemera: programs, Eunice Beecher's ticket to unveiling of Beecher statue., 1888-1941 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Memorials (including poems by William E. Davenport)., 1887-1927 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Memorial pamphlets., 1888 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Memorial programs., 1891 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Memorial addresses., 1895, 1897, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Memorial pamphlets., 1903 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Plymouth Chimes., 1914, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Memorial pamphlets., 1923, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Memorial magazines: Brooklyn Eagle Library., 1900 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Memorial magazines., 1903 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - The Congregationalist and Christian World (January 2)., 1904 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Memorial magazines., 1913, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Brooklyn memorial proclamation of Henry Ward Beecher Anniversary Day (June 9)., 1958 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - History of the 13th Regiment., 1894 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Personal reminiscences by church members (typescripts)., circa 1904 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Personal reminiscences by church members (manuscripts)., 1881-1947 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Tape recorded reminiscences of Plymouth by Grace Parsons Hart., 1958 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Reminiscences of William E. Davenport, with typescript of Beecher 1886 lecture on industrial conditions., 1927-1935 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Printed reminiscences by Beecher's friends., 1887, 1910-11 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Henry Ward Beecher as Preacher and Reformer by Joseph Cook., 1887 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - General printed memorials of Beecher., 1887-1978 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - General printed memorials of Beecher: Brooklyn Daily Eagle newsclipping (October 13)., 1913 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Loose clippings on Beecher, family and church., circa 1883-circa 1927 (Box 14, Folder 9-13)
    - Scrapbook pages of clippings on Beecher, family and church., circa 1876-1900 (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
    - Loose clippings on Beecher, family and church., 1871-1913 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Henry Ward Beecher Missionary Circle: Organization and History., 1888-1918 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Henry Ward Beecher Missionary Circle: Business Records, including correspondence, photos, 1884, 1913-1926 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Plymouth Foreign Missionary Society: General Printed Material., 1871-1936 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Beecher Memorial Church: newspaper clipping., 1932 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Henry Ward Beecher Literary and Debating Society: 2 Minute Books., 1889-1894 (Box 16, Item 1)
- Series 2: Plymouth Church, 1824-circa 1980; 9.6 Cubic Feet
  The series is arranged in eight sections:
  Section 1: Publications (1854-1980)
  Section 2: Records (1851-1933)
  Section 3: Sunday School (1845-1962)
  Section 4: Church Organizations (1863-1949)
  Section 5: Pastors (1888-1955)
  Section 6: History (1856-1961)
  Section 7: General (1824-1978)
  Section 8: Scrapbooks (1854-1916)
  This series contains materials that primarily concern Plymouth Church. Although certain items document the church during Henry Ward Beecher's tenure, their primary use is in documenting the activities of the church, rather than those of Beecher. In addition to church records, this series includes papers of and regarding four of Beecher's successors at Plymouth Church. The series also includes some material from Church of the Pilgrims and, to a lesser extent, other churches in Brooklyn and elsewhere.
  The series contains church publications, including the monthly Plymouth Chimes, church bulletins, church manuals, articles of faith, miscellaneous programs, annual reports, and other print matter. Records of Plymouth Church in the series include those relating to membership, such as a parish book, a shareholders' book, pew rental charts, and a list of applicants to the church.
  The series includes materials pertaining to the Sunday/Sabbath Schools, such as rosters, hymn books, sheet music, and programs for Sunday School events. The many organizations that were affiliated with Plymouth Church and Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims are represented in this section with material such as programs, membership rosters, and news clippings. The organizations represented include the Plymouth League, the Bethel Mission, Work Committee, Men's and Women's Clubs, the Arbuckle Institute, Plymouth Institute, and Plymouth Church house.
  Lyman Abbott, Newell Dwight Hillis, J. Stanley Durkee, and L. Wendell Fifield, the four pastors immediately following Henry Ward Beecher at Plymouth, are represented in the series with writings, sermons, news clippings, and ephemera. The series also includes materials pertaining to the general history, architecture, and notable members and leaders of Plymouth Church. Materials relating to Paxton Hibben's 1927 biography of Beecher are in the series. Several scrapbooks compiled by members of the congregation are found in the series; among these are one compiled with substantive annotations by Horatio C. King (circa 1901-1907) and one with political ephemera from the 1870s-1880s.
  - Section 1: Publications
    - Church Manuals., 1854, 1867, 1874, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Church Manuals., 1931 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Church Manuals., 1940 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Articles of Faith and Principles and Rules, 1884, 1895, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Letter-Missive." Sent to Congregational Churches., 1876 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Plymouth Pulpit: Sermons by HWB., 1869-1870 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - List of Church leaders., 1882, 1884, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Bulletins., 1888-1921 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Bulletins., 1935-1942 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Bulletins., 1958-1963 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Bulletins- Polytechnic Baccalaureate ceremony., 1930, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Programs: Concerts., 1869-1892 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Programs., 1876, 1892, 1937-1938, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Anniversary programs., 1900-1937 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Programs: Miscellaneous events at Plymouth, not Plymouth specific, 1930-1932, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Lenten and Christmas programs., 1934-1960 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Plymouth Triangle magazine., 1879 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Plymouth Chimes: bound volume, 1877-1895 (Box 57, Item 1)
      The spine of the volume is broken and the edges of the pages are brittle and fragile. Researchers should handle with care.
      The first two issues had come loose from the binding and have been separately foldered for preservation. Researchers should use the provided preservation photocopies.
      Also includes a program for the 77th Plymouth organ concert, 1873, which was the gift of Frank J. Wilder.
    - Plymouth Chimes., 1885-1899 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Plymouth Chimes (18 folders)., 1900-1915 (Box 18, Folder 2-19)
    - Plymouth Chimes (8 folders)., 1916-1922 (Box 19, Folder 1-8)
    - Plymouth Chimes., 1923 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Plymouth Chimes calender., 1891-1892, 1902-1908 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Plymouth News., 1952-1953 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - The Plymouth Hymnal: For the Church the Social Meeting and the Home., 1895 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Organ and window information, including programs., 1905, 1907 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Endowment Funds Pamphlet., 1932 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Plymouth Church and Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims - general church information., 1935 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - $300,000 Capital Restoration Program pamphlet., circa 1980 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Notes to visitors., circa 1930s-circa 1940s (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - "Reply to Membership Inquiries"., circa 1910 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Membership information and description of Church., circa 1960s (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Section 2: Records
    - Pew Rental Receipts., 1851-1853, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Shareholders' book., 1858 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Applicants to the Church., 1868-1870 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Annual Reports., 1889, 1891, 1896-1897, 1903 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Subscribers to Semi-centennial fund, circa 1897 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Plymouth Church Pew Rental Charts., 1900-1924 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Parish Book., 1904 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Treasurer's Report., 1920 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Minutes - Church Work Committee., 1920-1921 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Report to Annual Meeting., 1923 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Church of the Pilgrims: Treasurer's reports., 1925-1926, 1931-1933 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Lists of members., 1925, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Plymouth Church of the Pilgrims: Financial Reports., 1934-1937 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Former address of members., circa 1925 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Card-file Index to the Beecheriana Library at Plymouth Church House, undated (Box 76)
  - Section 3: Sunday School
    - Church of the Pilgrims- S.S. Record Book., 1845-1907 (Box 58, Item 1)
    - Programs: Sunday School Concert and festival., 1853-1962 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Sunday school ephemera., 1859-1882 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Hymn Book: Book of Praise., 1875 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Sunday school attendance book., 1875-1876 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Sunday School roll book and roster; photo of first Sabbath School building in Brooklyn., 1879-1880 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Santa Claus: A Christmas Cantata (play by S.S.)., circa 1880 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Sunday School Hymn Book, Church of the Pilgrims., 1894 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Plymouth Sunday School: Christmas Carols., 1904 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Sunday school vacation questions., 1906 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - "Land of My Children" from Plymouth Bible Class., 1918 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Mayflower Sunday School: Annual Reports, 1923-1925, 1928-1929 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Sunday School Manuals: Catechism, Lenten Manuals., 1939, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Weekday school roster., undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Section 4: Church Organizations
    - Arbuckle Institute., 1914-1921 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Plymouth Institute: Letter indicating name change and publicity pamphlets., 1918 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Plymouth Institute- Play Programs., 1934 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Plymouth Institute: Report., 1939 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Plymouth Institute: Misc. Organizations., 1937 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Bethel Mission Scrapbook, 1863-1904 (Box 59, Item 1)
    - "Bethel Mission" newsletter (October)., 1873 (Box 73, Item 1)
    - Bethel Scrapbook Pages., circa 1869-1891 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Bethel Mission ephemera., circa 1877-1881, 1891 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Bethel Branch bulletin., 1900 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Bethel Closing, Newsclippings., 1899-1929 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Benevolence Fund: "Yearbook" list of food items donated and purchased by the Church "Yearbook" listing donations and disbursements of Thanksgiving items., 1920-1934 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Benevolence Fund account book., 1934-1935 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Church Work Committee., 1889, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Henry Ward Beecher Memorial Association: Scrapbook presented by John Low, Jr. and Horatio C. King., 1917 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Ladies of the Foreign Missionary Society - "Favorite Quotations of Plymouth People"., circa 1900 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Mayflower Mission Sunday School Reminisces., circa 1945 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Plymouth Church Choir Book., 1871 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Plymouth League Constitution., 1887 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Plymouth League programs and ephemera., 1896-1902 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Plymouth Men's Club- Constitution and Bylaws., 1917 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration: Preparation., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration: Bills and Receipts., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration: Correspondence, invitations and replies., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration: Correspondence, acknowledgements., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration: Programs., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration: Speeches., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration: Press Releases., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration: Miscellaneous., 1940 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Plymouth Rock Celebration scrapbook., 1940-1941 (Box 60, Item 1)
    - Plymouth Work Committee Fund: Misc. Program., 1896 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Tandem Club Constitution., 1949 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Thanksgiving Cheer Fund- Correspondence and receipts., 1925-1932 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Women's Home Missionary Society., 1899, 1911-12 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Women's Guild of Plymouth Church., 1927 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Church of the Pilgrims: Benevolence Fund, Annual Report., 1930 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - List of women who contributed to Plymouth., circa 1920s (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Activities., 1937-1941 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Section 5a: Pastors - Lyman Abbott
    - "Installation Council" proceedings., 1890 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Writings, sermons, lectures., 1888-1911 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence., 1891-1896 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous- Programs and clippings., 1895-1922 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Clippings., circa 1898 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Section 5b: Pastors - Newell Dwight Hillis
    - Writings, sermons, lectures., 1900-1920 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: from servicemen., 1918-1919 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Better America Lectures., circa 1919-1920 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Search Committee for Hillis's successor, memorials, 1925, 1929, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Sermons: Brooklyn Eagle Reprints., 1911-1915 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous- Ephemera, programs and clippings., circa 1900-1929 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Book: Great Books as Life's Teachers., 1899 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Book, A Yearbook of Quotations from Contemporary Women, by Mrs. NDH., 1927 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Book: Aftersermon Prayers., 1930 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Section 5c: Pastors - J. Stanley Durkee